<recipe>
	<name>Rustic Apple Tart with Pear Styling</name>
	<notes>When I went to Bormio they served these perfectly styled pastry tarts made out of a lot of butter and some apples.  When I returned home I found a recipe in "Baking With Challenge Butter" (also recently arrived) that looked remarkably like it, only using pears.

They are all about the paesano rolled-crust style which looks pretty good but at the Hotel Rezia, you -know- they used the magic pan.

Magic pan!  Hey!</notes>
	<ingredients>
		<ingredient>
			<quantity>1/4 cup</quantity>
			<ingredient_name>sliced almonds</ingredient_name>
			<preparation></preparation>
		</ingredient>
		<ingredient>
			<quantity>2 1/4 cups</quantity>
			<ingredient_name>all-purpose flour</ingredient_name>
			<preparation></preparation>
		</ingredient>
		<ingredient>
			<quantity>1/2 cup</quantity>
			<ingredient_name>sugar</ingredient_name>
			<preparation></preparation>
		</ingredient>
		<ingredient>
			<quantity>2 sticks (1 cup)</quantity>
			<ingredient_name>butter</ingredient_name>
			<preparation>real cold</preparation>
		</ingredient>
		<ingredient>
			<quantity>1/4 cup</quantity>
			<ingredient_name>water</ingredient_name>
			<preparation></preparation>
		</ingredient>
		<ingredient>
			<quantity>1 1/2 lbs</quantity>
			<ingredient_name>Bosc Pears or Golden Delicious Apples (about four of the latter)</ingredient_name>
			<preparation></preparation>
		</ingredient>
	</ingredients>
	<preparation>In a blender grind 1 tbl almonds, 1 tbl flour, and 2 tsp sugar and set aside.

Reserve 1 tbl butter from stock.  Dice and cut in with 2 cups flour and 1/4 cup sugar.  Mix with a fork until find crumbs form.  Add 1/4 cup water and mix to a soft dough.

Roll out dough onto a large square of baking parchment to roughly a 15" disc.

Core apples and slice thinly.  Sprinkle previously whriled almond powder on pastry, leaving a 2" space to roll up the crust. Arrange apples artfully (starburst, anyone?) onto the pastry and roll edges pizza stylee.

Coat apples with remaining almonds and 2tsp sugar

Brush pastry rim with the melted remains of that 1tbl of butter from earlier (yay!  1/2 lb!) and sprinkle 1tsp sugar around edge(*).

Challenge and the good people at sunset think you should cook at 400 degrees for 40 minutes but that's an awful lot.  My apples and edges ended up looking a bit burnt.  

Were I to make it again, and I figure I shall given that it was devoured 'ere I got there, I might try something in the range of 350-375 for about the same time and see what came up


* - 6/25/05 -- damn, forgot to do that!</preparation>
	<primary_category>Desserts</primary_category>
	<secondary_categorys>
		<secondary_category>**New06</secondary_category>
		<secondary_category>Apples</secondary_category>
		<secondary_category>Made For Butter</secondary_category>
		<secondary_category>Makes You Fat</secondary_category>
		<secondary_category>Bill's Favorite</secondary_category>
	</secondary_categorys>
	<source_name>"Baking With Challenger Butter" ($2UPCs/S+H) 2002, Sunset Publishing Corp. (Dublin, CA)</source_name>
	<source_date>12</source_date>
	<entry_app>Veronica</entry_app>
	<cdate>06/25/2005</cdate>
	<mdate>05/24/2009</mdate>
	<user>billp</user>
	<safe_name>Rustic_Apple_Tart_with_Pear_Styling</safe_name>
</recipe>
