<recipe>
  <name>Scandinavian Christmas Bread</name>
  <safe_name>Scandinavian_Christmas_Bread</safe_name>
  <yield_count>10</yield_count>
  <yield_measure>Servings</yield_measure>
  <notes>A Christmas-Morning favorite around the Pollock household.  This is extra-good warm out of the oven or, even  better, sliced and stuck under the broiler with a little butter added and grilled crispy. </notes>
  <prep_time></prep_time>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient>
      <quantity>2 Tbl</quantity>
      <ingredient_name>active dry yeast (2 1/2 packets)</ingredient_name>
      <preparation></preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <quantity>1 Tbl</quantity>
      <ingredient_name>sugar</ingredient_name>
      <preparation></preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <quantity>1/4 cup</quantity>
      <ingredient_name>warm water</ingredient_name>
      <preparation></preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <quantity>2 cups</quantity>
      <ingredient_name>milk</ingredient_name>
      <preparation></preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <quantity>1/2 cup</quantity>
      <ingredient_name>shortening</ingredient_name>
      <preparation></preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <quantity>1/2 cup</quantity>
      <ingredient_name>sugar</ingredient_name>
      <preparation></preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <quantity>2 tsp</quantity>
      <ingredient_name>salt</ingredient_name>
      <preparation></preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <quantity>2 tsp</quantity>
      <ingredient_name>ground cardamom </ingredient_name>
      <preparation></preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <quantity>6 1/2 cups</quantity>
      <ingredient_name>all-purpose flour</ingredient_name>
      <preparation></preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <quantity>1 cup</quantity>
      <ingredient_name>fruitcake mix or candied cherries</ingredient_name>
      <preparation>cut into 1/4" cubes</preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <quantity>1 cup</quantity>
      <ingredient_name>raisins</ingredient_name>
      <preparation></preparation>
    </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <preparation>Soften raisins by putting them in  small amount of hot water.  Prepare candied fruit by dicing and shaking them in a bag with a little flour to coat and separate the fruit.  

In a medium bowl dissolve the yeast and 1 tablespoon sugar in 1/4 cup warm water. 

In a saucepan, scald milk: bring to 180F in a saucepan over medium heat while stirring constantly -- small bubbles should form.  Stir in shortening and let cool for 15 minutes.

Transfer milk mixture to a big mixing bowl and add 1/2 cup sugar, salt and ground cardamom seed. Mix in 2 cups flour, 1 cup at a time.  If using a mixer, start with the paddle attachment.

Stir in yeast mixture.  Add in 2 cups flour, 1 cup at a time.  Add candied fruit, raisins, and chopped almonds, mixing well.   If using a mixer, switch to the dough hook at this point.

Stir in 2 1/2 cups of remaining flour, 1 cup at a time.

Turn dough out on a floured board and kneed well.   Place dough in a greased bowl and cover with a damp cloth.

Put dough in a warm place (about 80F) or in a warmed oven (turned off) with a pan of hot water on the bottom rack.  Let dough rise until double, about 45 mins.   Punch down and let rise until double again.

Punch down and cut into 2 equal sections.  Knead well.  Form round loaves and place them on a cookie sheet.  Cover with a damp cloth and double once more.

Preheat the oven to 350F.  Bake loaves for about 35 minutes -- the tops should be golden brown.
</preparation>
  <primary_category>Breakfast</primary_category>
  <secondary_categories>
    <secondary_category>Bill's Favorite</secondary_category>
    <secondary_category>Makes You Fat</secondary_category>
  </secondary_categories>
  <entry_app>Veronica</entry_app>
  <cdate>01/31/2006</cdate>
  <mdate>12/26/2009</mdate>
  <user>billp</user>
</recipe>
