<publisher>

<!-- fuck this - should not be necessary...  -->
  <title>Dr. Leta Jackson's Cooking Omnibus</title>
  <copyright>2017.  From the collection of Leta Jackson.  Most recipes were hand-written.  Authors are cited when available.</copyright>
  <author_cite>William Pollock</author_cite>
  <project_url>http://billpollock.com/eathappy/show/gramma</project_url>
  <publishing_history>
     <edition>1st Edition, Fall 2017</edition>
  </publishing_history>  
  <sort>primary category</sort><!-- alt title, but falls through for anything not primary category -->
  <paper_width_inches>6</paper_width_inches>
  <paper_height_inches>9</paper_height_inches>
  <aux id="Introduction"><![CDATA[
My grandmother Leta was a powerful launching force of my cooking journey.  I was sure I was going
to find some treasure-trove of beloved memories but largely the recipes were From A Different Time
and alien.

My grandmother died when I was fairly young; when I took a hard critical look back
I recall as many recipes I suffered through (wilted spinach salad, dressed oranges -- sound great
now) as treasured with all my heart (berry + apple pie).

I think my grandmother's pleasure in cooking was her great takeaway.  This collection, converted
from her own recipe cards, are rather no-nonsense.  My grandmother's care in craft shines
through; like I do not recall a kitchen destroyed by a day's effort.  Gum was always 
humming her way through the cooking.  She encouraged me to help with pie and I'm sure other
tasks.  She always made cooking seem /cool/.

I recall her cooking dishes for numerous luncheons and she had the same care in craft as she did cooking for her family and meals were equally formal throughout.

While care-taking for my father and his home in 2004 I came across a memorable green card box, I believe with a bottom that made me concerned for rust and conservatorship.  In the box were all my grandmother's recipe cards, some typed and a handful of commercial recipes but the rest in her or my mother's or a friend's hand.  Some of them bear great battle stains; I wish at this stage that I had some sort of stained-ness category to apply as a rating.

Recipes are kind of fragile, precious things.  To me, these so more than most.  

This project sat on the back burner and pulled off occasionally when a stretch of quiet would appear on the horizon, when I wanted something to work on with a concrete endpoint.  I wish the scans were a little better, but even then the indigo fountain pen made somewhat inscrutable strokes with medical notations sprinkled here and there.

The scanning took place in 2004 and the final entry was submitted in 2017.

]]></aux>
  <aux id="Copyright Blurb"><![CDATA[
WARNING: while all efforts have been made to ensure the dishes in this cookbook are safe and nutritious, no warranties are made as to the overall safety or nutrition of any recipe.  Recipes marked as "Untried" have not been tested.  This book is targeted at the moderately experienced cook:  use your best judgment when ingredients or techniques seem unsound.

Published in 2017 with the assistance of EatHappy 3.0, Adobe InDesign, Aspell, with finishing through LibreOffice 5.
]]></aux>
</publisher>
