<recipe>
  <source_page></source_page>
  <safe_name>Armenian_Cracker_Bread</safe_name>
  <primary_category>Bread</primary_category>
  <preparation>Preheat oven to 450F.  In a small bowl beat eggs and milk

In a large bowl mix  flour, sugar and salt.  Cut in shortening until mixture resembles coarse crumbs.  Gradually blend in egg mixture and mix until dough pulls away from sides of bowl.

On a floured board lightly knead dough to form a smooth ball.  Divide the dough into 4 parts -- wrap 3 of them in plastic wrap to keep them from drying out.  Roll out and bake one portion at a time.

On the floured surface roll out a ball of dough to about 1/8 inch thick.  Add flour as needed to prevent sticking.  Reshape into a ball, then roll out again to a 14-inch circle.

Transfer carefully to a greased baking sheet or pizza pan.  Brush lightly with water, then sprinkle with 1 teaspoon sesame seed.

Place a shallow pan of hot water on bottom rack of oven.  Place baking sheet on rack above it and bake 3 minutes.  Remove water, reduce heat to 300F and bake until bread is blistered, feels dry to the touch, and is lightly browned (12 to 15 minutes).  Cool on a wire rack.

Repeat rolling and baking with remaining portions of dough.

When rounds of bread are crisp and cool, break into irregular pieces and serve.</preparation>
  <yield_count></yield_count>
  <yield_measure>Servings</yield_measure>
  <untried>1</untried>
  <cdate>01/09/2005</cdate>
  <prep_time></prep_time>
  <name>Armenian Cracker Bread</name>
  <source_date>1987</source_date>
  <source_name>California Culinary Academy "Regional American Classics"</source_name>
  <notes></notes>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>eggs</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>2</quantity>
      <preparation/>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>milk</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1 cup</quantity>
      <preparation/>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>all-purpose flour</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>4 cups</quantity>
      <preparation/>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>sugar</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1 1/2 tsp</quantity>
      <preparation/>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>salt</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1 1/2 tsp</quantity>
      <preparation/>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>shortening</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1/4 cup</quantity>
      <preparation/>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>sesame seeds</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>4 tsp</quantity>
      <preparation/>
    </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <mdate></mdate>
</recipe>
