<recipe>
  <notes>**UNTRIED** I do like the idea of chunk chicken salad sandwitches but the last attempt I tried was a disasterous  conversion of an English (as in UK) recipe that (a) didn't taste anything like the original and (b) was  rather horrid.

From the SF Chronicle, 23 April 2003</notes>
  <yield_count>4</yield_count>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Chicken Breasts</ingredient_name>
      <unknown_1>05065</unknown_1>
      <quantity>2</quantity>
      <preparation>"plump, Boneless And Skinless"</preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Garlic Cloves</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>2</quantity>
      <preparation>Chopped</preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Lemon Or Lime</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1/2</quantity>
      <preparation>Juiced</preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Tandoori Paste</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>2 Tbl</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Vegetable Oil</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1 Tbl</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Mayo</ingredient_name>
      <unknown_1>04018</unknown_1>
      <quantity>4 Tbl</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Unflavored Yogurt</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>4 Tbl</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Dried Mint</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1 Tsp</quantity>
      <preparation>Crushed</preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Lettuce Leaves</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1 - 2 Per Sandwitch</quantity>
      <preparation>Torn Into Pieces</preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Cucumber</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1/2</quantity>
      <preparation>Seeded And Diced</preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Pitas</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>4</quantity>
    </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <name>Chicken Tikka Pita Sandwitch</name>
  <yield_measure>Servings</yield_measure>
  <category>
    <category>Sandwich</category>
    <category>Untried</category>
  </category>
  <preparation>Combine the chicken, garlic and lime juice.  Let marinate for 15 minutes or so, then add the tandoori paste and let marinate for as long as possible:  30 minutes is good, an hour over overnight is even better.

Rub the chicken with the oil, then cook it:  broil, grill, or brown in a nonstick frying pan.  When the chicken is just cooked through, about 5 or 6 minutes per side (be careful not to overcook), transfer to a plate and let cool.

Cut the chicken into bite-sized pieces.  Set aside.

Mix together mayonnaise and yogurt then stir in the mint.   Set aside.

Brush the pitas on one side with water the heat either in a  toaster or in a heavy nonstick frying pan.  They should puff up, making it easy to split them to form a pocket.

Into each pocket place a few pieces of chicken, a spoonful of sauce, a sprinkling of cucumber, a little lettuce, more chicken and so on, until the ingredients are used up and/or the pitas can't hold any more. Garnish with onion, tomato and cilantro/mint then serve.</preparation>
</recipe>
