<recipe>
  <name>Granola (Jessamyn West Is A)</name>
  <preparation>Mix the dry and wet ingredients together yet separately, dry ingredients mixed into a bowl and wet ingredients into a large measuring cup. Evenness is happiness in the granola game, so be sure to mix everything together smoothly.  Quality ingredients on the honey and syrup do make a difference and "maple syrup" != "log cabin".  You are going to make hella killer granola here for the cheap, so go big and go Canadian Maple. 

Evenly pour the syrup you've made into the dry ingredients, making sure to mix thoroughly and ensure none of the dry ingredients stay that way.

Evenly spread the mix in a 13"x9" oven and bake for 15 minutes at 350F. Pull the pan out and quickly turn the granola, stirring in the dried fruit.   Bake an additional fifteen minutes or until golden brown. Remove from heat and let cool completely before serving or storing in an airtight container.

There is a wide variety of flavors one can get with this simple recipe and the most basic of elements: roasting time.  The key is to get the elements pretty nearly dry again or at least enough so that they'll adhere.   Given the candy-like nature of the recipe, I'm sure I could give you a measurable minimum point of core temperature you needed to reach for this to happen but I may be too lazy as of this edition to find it.

The important thing is that much of your "crunch" and the nature of it depends on how much of the sugar you caramelize and for how long -- shorter tends to be clumpier, longer "flakier".

 On my very first batch I went too long between checking and I had a fair amount of charred sugar sitting on sad, naked looking oat flakes. Never you fear if this happens to you, though.  The blackened flakes will give your milk a nice "coffee" flavor.

</preparation>
  <main_ingredient>Good For You!</main_ingredient>
  <yield_count>8</yield_count>
  <notes>Jessamyn West is this militant librarian living a modern bohemian lifestyle between Seattle and rural  Vermont.  She is an online writer, among other things and she'd had written an article to her readership  thereby  emasculating anyone who -ate- granola but did not -make- granola.  Anyone who has hung  around any sort of DIY movement for more than ten minutes without smelling like motor oil knows that   this is a common refrain, one that ends "because its much better than store-bought."  

I am willing to buy into many things, though breakfast cereal kind of boggles the imagination.  Making it  yourself is surprisingly good, though its really in another class of food from what you get at most any  kind of store.   Not quite fair to even compare the two.    This is good "mountain aire" stylee granola in that one bowl will generally leave even the  biggest eaters  pretty well packed in.</notes>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Rolled Oats</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>2 1/2 Cups</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Sliced Almonds</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1/2 Cup</quantity>
      <preparation>(pronounced "aamonds")</preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Wheat Germ</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1/2 Cup</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Sunflower Seeds, Roasted, Unsalted</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1/2 Cup</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Raisins, Craisins, Etc</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1 Cup</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Cooking Oil</ingredient_name>
      <unknown_1>04518</unknown_1>
      <quantity>1/2 Cup</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Honey</ingredient_name>
      <unknown_1>19296</unknown_1>
      <quantity>1/2 Cup</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Maple Syrup</ingredient_name>
      <unknown_1>19353</unknown_1>
      <quantity>1/2 Cup</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Vanilla</ingredient_name>
      <unknown_1>02050</unknown_1>
      <quantity>1-2 Tsp</quantity>
    </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <category>
    <category>Breakfast</category>
  </category>
  <yield_measure>Servings</yield_measure>
</recipe>
