<recipe>
  <main_ingredient>Bill's Favorite</main_ingredient>
  <notes><![CDATA[This is a bit of an unusual Mac and Cheese, having upon its top a golden breadcrumb and butter mixture  which is probably the best part of the mix.  Any Mac and Cheese without it looks straight-up naked.

This was my number-one favorite dish when I was a kid and the one most often requested as a birthday  treat.  This makes a nice, creamy Mac & Cheese that is well worth the effort.]]></notes>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Butter Or Margarine</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>2 Tbl</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Flour</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>2 Tbl</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Milk</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1 Cup</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Dry Mustard</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1/2 Tsp</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Salt</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1 Tsp</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Worcestershire Sauce</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>2-3 Shakes</quantity>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Cheddar Cheese</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>1/3 Lb</quantity>
      <preparation>Cubed Or Shredded</preparation>
    </ingredient>
    <ingredient>
      <ingredient_name>Macaroni</ingredient_name>
      <quantity>2 Cups</quantity>
    </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <name>Mom's Macaroni And Cheese</name>
  <yield_measure>Servings</yield_measure>
  <category>
    <category>Main Dish</category>
  </category>
  <preparation>Melt butter in double boiler and gradually add flour to it.  Cook for "a few minutes" (e.g. until smooth and well-integrated looking) and then add milk a little at a time.

After sauce thickens (evens) add spices and cheese.  Stir occasionally until cheese melts.

While sauce cooks, boil water, add 1 tsp salt and cook macaroni.  If the macaroni finishes before the sauce, rinse the macaroni in a colander and put cover with cold water.  When sauce is ready, drain macaroni.

In 1.5 quart  casserole dish, mix macaroni and sauce in equal portions until dish is filled. Top with bread crumb mix:  2 T melted butter mixed with 1/3 cup dry bread crumbs.

**I have found that this recipe has some problems scaling -- I made a triple batch of it one time and was adding flour until the cows came home AFTER adding the cheese to offset the fluid volume.  The sauce is supposed to be thick almost like, um, well...

Thick, in any regard.

**I find that getting the bread crumb mixture right is kind of tricky to get properly hydrated without being overly saturated with butter, but here's a trick:  I don't actually have a double boiler, I just have two pots and I've found that if you ditch the water from the "water" pot, you've got yourself a nice warm pan to melt sufficient butter in and add bread crumbs -to-, and that does the trick pretty nice.

**I like a little heat in everything.  I've added a bit (2T) of Sriracha to the cheese mixture as it cooked and it combined nicely with the Worchestershire and the sharp cheddar.</preparation>
</recipe>
